Does this look okay?
It doesn't look weird, does it?
Today, I'm going on
my first date with Kazehaya.
On that note, this skirt
feels a little shorter than I expected.
I hope this is okay.
Please, no mistakes today.
I... I kept you waiting again. I'm sorry.
You're good. I just figured
I'd show up here a little bit early.
That was my decision.
Nothin' like a bunch'a nerves
to get you outta bed early!
- Tha-- that was me too!
- Really?
Uh, uh-huh.
That's cool!
Whoa!
- Can I have some?
- Mmm.
It's so good.
Uh-oh.
- Oh.
- Darn it. Here come the happy tears.
Today,
is a day I'll never forget.
- Mmm, actually...
- Hmm?
I wish you a very happy birthday!
Huh? Wha--
It's your birthday.
Truth is, I feel terrible saying this,
but I only found out a few days ago
that today is your birthday.
Please forgive me
for not planning a celebration.
Wait. It's fine. Really!
I know it's a little late,
but... I did manage to find you a present.
It would make me
really happy if you accepted it.
Y-- you mean it?
Here.
I hope you and Maru
will have lots of fun with this toy.
Whoa! Thank you.
And this too.
May it bring lots of joy to you and Maru.
- Huh? Two toys?
- Nice!
And there's also this.
I thought you and Maru
might find this enjoyable.
Thank you.
Now that I think about it,
I might've accidentally gotten
more birthday presents for Maru
than for Kazehaya.
- Here.
- Hm? What's this?
I really loved
the cellphone strap you gave me that day.
Uh, thanks a lot. I appreciate it.
Funny story about that strap.
How I went out and bought it
on the same day I heard
you couldn't make it
to the Christmas party we all had.
I know you must have felt
really upset about that.
Sorry I couldn't help.
I wanted to get you something though.
Not just for the class present exchange
but a gift for you specifically.
When I saw the strap,
it reminded me of you.
So I got it.
Thank you for this.
I'll cherish it.
What do I do?
I was hoping it would make him happy.
But... I'm the one who's happy.
- Why don't we sit here?
- Okay.
It's pretty empty.
- Why not put that on a chair?
- Y-- yeah.
That's cool.
The seats here recline.
Yeah, it's not like the movies.
I'm really happy.
Well, first star's out.
That's Lyra's... Vega? I think?
Some say "Orihime."
Vega's a magnitude zero star, isn't it?
Better keep your eyes
on the road, or you'll trip!
Yeah.
Um... thanks for that.
Wait.
- Mm?
- Could we... talk a bit?
Honestly... I wasn't sure
whether it was a good idea
to give this to you.
It's not exactly the right season
for this, and it's a bit unwieldy.
I really hope this isn't too much trouble.
Oh.
It's the hat I was going to
give you for Christmas but couldn't.
My dad got it.
I know it was an honest mistake,
but I... I knitted it just for you.
I know this must look like
I'm just giving you my dad's hat...
You don't have to wear it
if you don't want to.
- I also...
- Hm?
I brought the chocolates I couldn't
give you on Valentine's Day.
I made sure yours had a bit more chocolate
than the others.
But I was too scared to give it to you.
These are the presents I had always wanted
to give to you... but never could.
That's really good!
I'm... so happy!
I... I still don't know
what a girlfriend's job really is, but...
Kuronuma.
It's not a job.
It really isn't.
You just gotta be yourself.
Am I contradicting myself?
I'm so happy!
So happy that I wish...
time would just hurry and fly right by us.
So that... being together with you
all the time can finally feel normal.
But that would be such a waste.
I couldn't do that.
Sorry, I thought I was the only one
who felt this way.
I'm so happy.
Kazehaya said
he feels the same way that I do.
FROM ME TO YOU: KIMI NI TODOKE
3RD SEASON
EPISODE 1
THERE'S NO WAY I WOULD HATE YOU
Summer is a time
rife with temptations.
Many excitements will assail you.
But as a student,
your job is to stay focused!
Summer vacation is not an excuse
to get carried away.
So remember
to conduct yourselves with propriety.
It's finally summer!
- We're on vacation!
- Yeah!
What are you so excited about?!
Weren't any of you listening?!
Excitement is the enemy here!
It'll trip you up!
As a student, your duty is to
focus on your studies.
She's so right! Pick up a book!
Those poor kids.
You're one to talk! Weren't you just
on the verge of failing all your classes?!
You and me, Chizu.
We have to pay money to come here
and advance our education over the summer.
They're the lucky ones who get to waltz in
and do that for free.
I know we're here 'cause your single butt
needs a way to pass the time--
Last I checked, you're single too!
And you, Kazehaya?
I'm taking summer classes too.
- Oh cool! Same as me!
- Yeah, right. You're not going.
So when shall we meet up?
Speakin' of which,
we gettin' together soon?
Yeah, duh!
It's summer vacation.
All right, I'll see you in class.
I'll keep in touch, okay?
M-- me too!
But... I'm not sure
what to talk to him about.
Don't think too hard about it.
You could say, "I'm tired,"
"It's hot outside," or "I just woke up."
Anything really.
Just like that?
I... I hope it won't bother him.
No, no, no, no, no.
Even though we've officially
become a couple,
I still don't have a single clue
what the first step is.
Man, I feel ya.
For the most part, dating's really just
about spending a lot of time together.
Going places together and being together.
As long as it's just you two,
don't sweat the details.
- I see.
- Oh!
It's setting in.
Sawako really does have a boyfriend now.
I'm lonely.
You're lonely?
Mm-hmm. Course I am.
Curse you, Kazehaya!
I mean, I am still happy for you, but...
I'm so glad!
Wait! Maybe this means
we can do things like this.
Or even like that!
We can see each other all the time
because it's summer.
Yay!
Hey, Chizu, Ayane... I love you.
I love you too! Always and forever!
Wait a second.
When you two get together,
something is bound to happen eventually.
I mean, you are a couple now.
- Huh?
- Huh? Wait, I don't follow.
When you're alone together,
it's only natural.
You'll hold hands.
Then you'll cuddle up.
And kiss.
Hold hands?
Cuddle up?
Kiss?!
No, thank you!
All of this is way more
than I can handle right now, I'm sorry!
Chill. It's not a big deal.
Don't be mean.
Oh, all right.
All these new feelings are totally normal,
but I get why
they'd be a little overwhelming.
Really?!
I mean, of course.
Oh, that reminds me, you still haven't
told us how your date went the other day.
- Yeah! We want all the details!
- Right. The date was...
- Huh?
We planetarium-ed.
I gave his gift to him.
But first, we bento-ed.
- Huh?
- What?
Hey, uh, what just happened?
I don't have a clue.
I'm sorry.
I've kept you out longer
than I should have. Let's head back.
After that, we walked home.
With enough space between us
to fit a third person.
Just like always.
Aw, that's my girl.
You've decided to attend
summer classes again, have you?
Such a scholar!
Huh! But kiddo, it's your summer vacation.
Why not shake things up a little, huh?
Like, I don't know,
inviting some friends over?
How about Chizu or Ayane?
What a good idea!
- Girls have all the fun at this age.
- I wonder...
-Is it time for me to tell Mom and Dad?
- ...invite your other friends too.
Um, I uh...
- Um?
So awkward!
How do other girls
have this conversation with their parents?
Maybe I should've asked Ayane for advice.
I'll keep in touch.
What'll we talk about?
How often will you text?
Can I text you sometimes too?
If I message you out of the blue,
would it bug you?
And what about summer break?
You asked me out last time.
So is it my turn to ask you out?
Being in a relationship
sends my brain into overdrive.
Oh, it's Kazehaya!
THIS IS MARU
MARU-CHAN IS SO CUTE
SENDING
Summer break.
It's been... a whole year...
since I started thinking
about Kazehaya like this.
But now, I think about him
a lot more than I did back then.
So much that it kinda hurts.
SUMMER CLASSES
MODERN LIT, ENGLISH, MATH
- I'm so tired!
- We've got English next.
Did you see Joe?
He had a fat stack of printouts.
For real?
- Hey, Ayane.
- Uh?
There's something I need to ask you about.
Uh, what's up?
Do you think it'd be appropriate
if I asked Kazehaya out after school?
Maybe we could...
Oh!
What are you talking about?
Of course it's fine!
Now go get 'im!
Kuronuma.
- Um, what if...
- Hm?
What if, after school today,
we studied together at the library?
Mmm, sounds good.
She always takes everything so seriously.
Oh well... typical Sawako.
Ayane!
That's a little familiar, don't you think?
But guys are supposed to call girls
by their first names, aren't they?
Maybe.
But you called Sawako "Sadako," right?
I'm just glad that it happened
before I started to like her.
Hang on...
- Do you call her Sadako on purpose?
- Uh--
Well, I have lots of reasons.
But don't you worry about it,
I only say it with love.
Yeah, of course you do.
Uh-oh! Next period's about to start.
Bye!
It's gonna be fine!
It's over!
School's finally out, Yano-chin!
- Where's Sawako?
- She went to the bathroom.
Then, I'll go too! Hm?
- About Sawako. Today, she's...
- Hm?
I'm trying to wear my uniform
like the other girls do.
Wait... something still isn't right.
Oh yeah, the button.
There! I undid my top button
just like the other girls!
How does it look? Does it look good?
A-- am I cute?!
I mean, a single button
can't hurt, can it?
Summer vacation
is not an excuse to get carried away.
So remember
to conduct yourselves with propriety.
It's fine!
One button won't ruin my conduct!
I might be overthinking things a bit.
Hey, Kuronuma!
Yeah, so Yoshida and Yano said
they were gonna go on and head out.
Huh?
I didn't get to see Chizu at all!
I bet leaving home early
was her plan all along.
Oh!
Your button's undone.
Oh! Yeah, it is!
It's kind of hot today, so I must've...
I'm so embarrassed!
I guess it didn't look good
on me after all!
There's absolutely no way I can tell him
I undid it on purpose!
Please, don't look too closely.
Stay just like that.
I'm really sorry, Kazehaya.
For some reason,
I'm just not myself at the moment.
I want to spend more time with you.
I want... to get closer...
to you.
Left field! Heads up!
Look,
the baseball team's practicing.
Kazehaya's behaving
like everything's normal.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm moving slow.
Uh-- No, it's not you.
I was the one walking too fast. I'm sorry.
Uh, no, it was me, I'm sure!
I end up walking behind you,
whenever I start looking at you.
Oh.
It's hard to look at you
if I'm next to you.
What did I say?!
I couldn't help but notice
that you look different today.
- Huh?
- Your uniform.
Oh! Does it look funny?
Uh--No, of course not.
Hang on.
If that's all you were worried about,
you should've just said something to me.
Sorry, I'm kind of shy.
I want to be with you.
I want to be next to you.
I want us to be close.
Is that weird?
It'll be fine.
All these new feelings are totally normal,
but I get why
they'd be a little overwhelming.
Could I
hold your hand for a bit?
Oh...
Uh... sorry!
I... messed up!
He noticed. I know he did.
Um, sorry! My mistake!
I didn't mean...
I just wanted...
I... I'm sorry for trying to touch you.
You were just acting the same way
you always do, and...
...and I... I was the only...
I'm so embarrassed.
Please don't hate me.
Same as always, huh?
Do I look like
I'm acting normal?
Sawako?
M-- Mom?
I... let go?
Are... you on your way home?
Yeah.
I haven't told my mom about Kazehaya yet.
She doesn't know.
It's a tricky subject.
I know I shouldn't be embarrassed. But...
This is so rude to her and Kazehaya.
Nice to meet you.
My name is Shota Kazehaya.
I'm in the same class as Kuronuma.
I also happen to be going steady
with her at the moment.
It's great to meet you.
Oh, dear!
Kazehaya!
Um... Hey, Mom?
I would also like to introduce him!
This is Kazehaya!
He's in the same class as me!
In addition to that, we are also dating!
Yes, I just heard.
We've been classmates for a while.
Ever since first year.
Also, because of Kazehaya's support,
I like school now.
It's really, really fun
to go to my classes.
It's also because he was there
that Ayane, Chizu, and I
managed to become friends.
That's not it.
Truth is, Kuronuma did it all on her own.
Thank you so much.
And it is such a pleasure
to finally meet you, Kazehaya.
We're having sukiyaki
for dinner tonight.
Huh?
Sukiyaki, you sillies!
Why don't you come
and have dinner with us, Kazehaya?
Only if you want to. No pressure.
Uh... I'd love to. I'll let my parents know.
- Sawako.
- Huh?
Why don't you give your father a call
and let him know?
It should be you.
Mm.
I guess... Mom must've already noticed.
She can tell
I regret not telling her myself
before we ran into each other.
Yeah. She's the one that
I told you about the other day.
I'm gonna go have dinner with her family.
Me too.
I'll tell him. I'll tell my father.
Hello, hello, Sawako!
Is something the matter?
Um, there's something I wanted to say.
Oh. Well, let's hear it.
And don't worry,
I'll be home soon!
So I've...
I've begun seeing someone at school.
Oh, and... he's coming over today.
He's... he's silent!
- Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh!
- It's going to be okay!
Your father is in for a long day.
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh!
My, my!
Who's this strapping young man with you?
Could this be your boyfriend?!
That's right!
- Nice to meet you.
- What a gentleman!
Your father's definitely
going to faint!
I'm... so nervous.
Is it just me?
Hey, Sawa! Who's your new friend?
Hello, sir!
- Oh my! Who's that with you, Sawako?
- Nice to meet you.
Oh!
Bringing your boyfriend over?
Nice to meet you!
- Well, he's quite the catch, isn't he?!
- Right?
Kazehaya, thanks so much.
Are you okay? Sorry about this.
Huh? Oh, uh...
Relax. I'm doing great.
Maybe a little nervous...
It's not hard to tell,
you're obviously very close
with all your neighbors.
And I'm really excited
to finally meet your mom and dad.
Huh?
I, uh... I think I'm actually
a lot more nervous than I'm letting on.
Maybe the most I've ever been!
Dad... Mom...
this person right here... is the one I love.
And this... is what he's like.
Come on, you kids,
let's get a move on.
Yes, ma'am.
It all felt so natural...
falling in love.
And wanting to hold hands.
There are things that I have to say
and things that I want to say.
I never thought... not for a moment,
that I would ever develop feelings
that I'd want to keep
all to myself.
Dad, this is Kazehaya.
Kazehaya, this is my father.
Good to meet you, sir.
I'm one of your daughter's classmates.
My name's Shota Kazehaya.
So here he is! Shota Kazehaya.
The boy I mentioned on the phone.
He's the one I've officially begun dating.
Wasn't I clear?
You were just
supposed to bring a friend over.
I don't think you were that specific.
I remember you saying
she should bring "someone" over.
Obviously, I meant she should've
brought home a girl, damn it!
But this is...
I cannot deny what's before me!
This person is obviously your boyfriend!
"Obviously"?
"My boyfriend"?!
Thank you, Dad!
What are you talking about?
The thing you just said.
I don't hear it very often.
Seriously, you really
think they're dating?
- Nuh-uh, there's no way.
- I don't know what kinda rumor you heard.
I never imagined there would come a day
when I'd hear you say that to me.
I'm embarrassed, but... I am happy.
- Aw!
- Uh-huh!
I...
Sir, I promise to treat her well.
Ahhhhh!
Yoko! My grinding stone, where is it?
Um, Dad?
I picked this up from our neighbor,
Ikeda, on my way home.
- Time to dig in.
- Wait, what?
What? Are you too good
for Mr. Ikeda's fish?
- Is that what you're telling me now?
- Thank you for the food.
Hoo! That's great. Props to Mr. Ikeda.
Exactly. His fish is always the best.
Is he...
trying to be a good host?
It might've sounded better to say,
"I prepared this fish for you myself."
Hmm.
No flaws in his chopstick technique.
And he remembered to say,
"Thanks for the food."
All right, come on now, dear.
I'm sure the sashimi's great,
but maybe you should change?
Sawako too.
Oh, but I...
Go on ahead.
I... I'll be right back.
You too, darling. Go on!
Yeah. You're right.
- Here you go.
- Uh-- Thank you.
- I'm really sorry for all the trouble.
- No, it's fine.
It's just that
my husband loves Sawako dearly.
Yeah, I figured that out pretty quick.
It was really easy to see.
There are so many people who care for her.
Uh-huh. Kazehaya, did we happen to talk
over the phone for a bit during Christmas?
Oh yeah, I remember!
That's what I thought.
You were such a big help.
Thank you so much.
She's a very logical girl, you know.
Because of that,
she does have a bit of a tendency
to put her feelings on the back burner.
That one time, however,
she was the one who brought it up.
She must've really wanted to go.
It made me so happy
to hear her tell me herself.
She's been smiling a lot lately.
I bet she's having a lot of fun.
You should know, that girl,
she might look shy,
but she does go after what she wants.
- Have you had your first fight yet?
- No, hasn't happened yet.
If it does,
I'd just wanna make up though.
By the way,
do you remember when you became official?
Uh, since the school festival.
So who asked who out first...
- Yoko!
- ...and what did they say?
- Stop! Enough questions!
- Ah, shoot.
And here I thought
I'd find out before Sawako got back.
Uh? What's wrong, dear?
Why did you get your winter hat out?
There was a mix-up at Christmas,
and my dad ended up with the hat instead.
Yeah, you see this? This hat?
Sawako made it just for me.
Kazehaya, I bet you don't
have anything like this.
Sorry but I do.
You've gotta be kidding?!
Wait, Dad,
why are you wearing that right now?
Well I... I, uh...
Why don't you wait with Sawako in her room
while I finish up the sukiyaki?
- Huh?!
- Hey!
Don't you think it's a little early
to be letting him go up there?
Maybe you should've thought of that
before taking up the whole kitchen
to sharpen your knife and delay dinner!
Um, shall we?
Yeah. Sure.
You keep that door open,
you hear me?
Yes! I'll keep that door open, sir!
I'm sorry for always putting you
in such awkward situations.
Why? I don't mind.
It's better to feel awkward now,
'cause when else will I get the chance?
Knowing there's someone
who likes me this way
makes me feel so safe.
'Til now, only my parents' words
of encouragement gave me that feeling.
Like when they'd say,
"It'll be okay," or "We love you."
- And here we are.
- Um, thanks.
My world's gotten
a little bigger now.
I get that same feeling
from Chizu, Ayane, and Kazehaya too.
Please, feel free to have a seat.
What's the matter?
Sorry. Just nerves, I guess.
I'm about as nervous as I was
when I first met your parents.
That's from
the school festival.
- Uh, yeah. I got it from Chizu.
- Oh, cool.
Look at that smile.
She's a very logical girl,
you know.
I-- I'm sorry.
Please don't hate me!
But how could I ever...
ever come to hate you?
Something I haven't been able
to figure out, no matter how hard I try,
is how to act in front of you.
Am I making mistakes?
Am I doing things right?
I was scared.
Worried it would all
suddenly come crashing down.
That's why I wanted time to pass quickly.
To finally reach a point
where things felt okay.
You know, mistakes aren't
the end of the world.
It's okay.
Yeah.
Everything's okay.
I love you.
Sukiyaki time, kiddos!
Argh! Why are you sitting
so close to her?!
- I'm sorry, it just sorta happened!
- Just sorta happened?!
- I'm the one who came over and sat down!
- No, that can't be true!
Help yourself
to some meat, Kazehaya.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Whoa there, kid!
The only thing
I've seen you pick up so far is the meat!
- Eat your vegetables!
- Y-- yes, sir.
- You need fiber too!
- He's making an effort!
Meat, veggies, meat, veggies,
veggies, meat, veggies!
Sir! Everything here's...
Kazehaya's also doing his best
to make conversation.
Settle down, dear.
He always tries his best to make sure
that I feel safe and comfortable.
I want to stop my worries
from getting in the way
and be faithful to Kazehaya's feelings.
That's who I want to be.
Um... here. Mom said to give you this.
- Hey, buster! Who you callin' "Mom"?!
- You're right, I'm sorry!
I can't finish all that.
- Sit down.
- Uh-- uh-- okay.
So, tell me, why Sawako?
A guy like you
has got to have options, right?
No, sir.
Your daughter's the only one for me.
You're lucky
you don't look anything like this!
- 'Cause otherwise I would never approve!
- Uh... No, I'm sorry.
How is Sawako performing in school?
She's a really good student.
And she does her fair share
of work for the student council too.
It seems like she's always
havin' a good time.
Hmm.
Don't worry about trying to grow up
into some extraordinary person.
If you're happy and healthy,
that's enough.
My Sawako has never been very forthcoming
when it comes to her emotions.
Even as a little girl.
But all that has changed.
It's clear, even to me,
she is finally having fun.
Chizu, Ayane, and yes, even you,
are probably a big part of why that is.
I thank you.
Uh, thank you for today.
Oh, you're welcome.
Thanks for having me for dinner.
Maybe you can come to my house next time.
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
'Cause I...
Never mind. Later!
Uh, get home safe!
I'm sorry. You were just acting
the same way you always do.
I bet... she doesn't realize it...
but I feel the same way.
When I'm with you, Kuronuma,
I just don't know what to do with myself.
FROM ME TO YOU: KIMI NI TODOKE
It's August.
Summer classes are almost done.
And then come Obon.
Maru, down!
Are you okay, Kuronuma? I'm sorry.
Ah! You're so big!
- Come on, Maru!
- You remember me?
- You're such a good puppy, aren't you?
- Heel! Sit!
When the Obon holidays begin,
you know the end of summer
is around the corner.
And so is the end of summer break.
I know I suggested
doing our homework together,
but now that I think about it,
you've probably already finished
your homework, right?
I have. But I do still have
lots of other things that I can study!
I called it!
Even so, I would've wanted
to come to your house anyway, Kazehaya.
Today, I'm extra nervous.
This'll be my first time
going to Kazehaya's place.
I wonder what his family will be like?
I hope I don't make a mistake.
I want to do my best
to be pleasant and cheerful.
Hopefully, I don't forget to smile
and make a good first impression.
I don't want to make them uncomfortable.
MARTINEZ
WIND SPORTS
I'm home!
Wait, does your family run a shop?
That's so interesting.
- I never would've imagined.
- Uh-- You mean, I never told you this?
Shota! There's a spot
on the glass next to you.
- Do you mind getting it?
- Uh... Oh, you mean here?
Uh, you'll have to forgive me.
My mom's pretty prickly.
What did you just call me? Oh--
Is this Sawako?
Sawako Kuronuma?
Thank you for coming by.
I've heard lots about you.
I'm Shota's mom. Nice to meet you.
They're so similar.
Their aura is exactly the same.
So that's why
you were cleaning your room.
Mom, stop!
Let's not go there, please.
So this... is Kazehaya's mom.
I'm Sawako Kuronuma!
Uh-- It's nice to meet you!
Oh, I totally forgot to smile!
Lighten up!
If you get any stiffer,
you might end up snapping like a twig!
S... stiff?
My, Sawako, your hair...
Was I supposed to tie it up?
You've got such beautiful locks.
So vibrant and shiny.
What a blessing it must be
to have a daughter.
To be honest with you, I often wish
I'd given birth to a little girl.
Jeez, my bad!
It's really Kazehaya's mom!
Oh, right. Um, this is for you.
It's a really good red-bean jelly
that my whole family likes a lot.
Wow, really? That's lovely.
Thank you so much. Oh, Sawako...
There's no need for all this formality.
You really didn't have to!
You might not be able to tell,
but my mom's really excited
'cause she loves red-bean jelly. Nice job!
Hey, knock it off!
Don't give it away!
I'm sorry my son is so difficult.
I'm sorry my mom is so difficult.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Don't just stand there!
Feel free to come on in.
Just so you know, she's always like this.
Oh-- Just like what, huh?
- Am I taking these boxes over there?
- That's right.
Do you mind? Since you're here, after all.
So that's how he was brought up.
It's what made him who he is today.
Sorry we spent
so much time talking before going in.
Huh? Oh no, it's fine.
I'm glad I got to meet your mom.
That's good. Man, what a relief.
- Oh, was there something worrying you?
- Yeah, of course, I was worried.
It's really important to me
that you like us.
Uh, thanks for having me over.
So what are your dad
and brother up to today?
- They're playing baseball.
- I see. Little league, I'm guessing?
Come on in.
This is Kazehaya's room!
Just pick any spot you like,
and make yourself comfortable.
- I'm gonna go get us some tea, okay?
- Uh, I'll help.
It's fine, don't worry about it.
Just relax and flip through a book or two.
Wow, what a huge collection!
He's got so many CDs too!
This is where he studies!
He sleeps on a bed!
So this... is where he lives!
I bet everything in this room
is a special thing he likes.
Oh, I really wanna do
a full, in-depth tour of the place.
But I shouldn't. Not without asking first.
I'm ba-- Duh!
You still haven't sat down yet?
I might've snuck a little peek
at your books, and your CDs,
and all other little aspects
of your personal life that are in here.
I'm not trying to hide those! If I were,
I wouldn't have invited you here.
Oh! Is that true?
Was there anything in particular
that caught your interest?
Whoa!
I haven't organized these yet.
I don't mind. Is it okay if I look?
It's a bit embarrassing
but I won't stop you.
I'll just look for a little bit.
- Is this from the test of courage?
- Oh yeah, it is! That was a fun night.
So that must be what it felt like
down on earth for everyone else.
"Down on earth"?
Ah, if we ever do this again,
I'd know exactly how to give everyone
an even bigger scare this time around.
- That's if it happens again.
- Huh?
If it does,
we'd be walking the course together.
- I'm going to walk it?
- Well, yeah, duh!
Together with you?
You don't want to?
I do. I'd like that.
Sorry... I just...
Can I tell you something?
Back then, on that night...
I already liked you.
Huh?! What do you mean, you liked me?
What do you mean by that?
And what does that mean
for us right now?
Mm-mmm. Actually, never mind!
Don't worry about it!
You don't have to tell me anything!
I like when people know how... to have fun.
You think... I'm like that?
Yeah. I do.
Always.
I can't sit this close!
I'm gonna go study.
Right now, he's... so close to me.
When I first started school,
I never imagined this would happen.
MATH II
Uh... when you...
when you called me by my name.
When you called me "Sawako."
Sawako.
Sawako Kuronuma. Right?
Sawa... ko.
Not "Kuronuma." And not "Sadako."
I want to fit the name "Sawako."
None of it really matters anymore.
As long as I treasure
the words he just said...
forever.
I'm not looking from behind
or from the side.
We see each other face-to-face.
And we both feel the same way.
I'm so glad.
I had no idea
that you knew back then.
When I called you by your first name.
You know, after the party?
- Huh?
- Wha--
Uh? Wait, which time
are you talking about, then?
Back when we first spoke.
We were standing in front of
the flowers, remember?
You asked if I was Sawako Kuronuma.
Oh, right!
I guess I technically did!
After what party though?
You mean the sports festival?
I don't understand.
At the after-party!
I called you by your name on the stairs!
I said "Sawako."
Why am I giving it away now?
I didn't know my feelings for you
began such a long time ago.
Me... me neither.
Sawako.
Sho... Shota.
Oh my!
Oh man!
- How am I supposed to study like this?
- I can't...
- Oh hey! Looks like my mom's calling me!
- Huh?
Hi, what's up?
Yeah.
Huh?
Sorry you got dragged into
doing errands with me, Kuronuma.
Would you two do me a huge favor
and go get a little ice cream for Tota?
Huh? Oh, I don't mind at all.
- I mean, we were supposed to study...
- Yeah, but I mean...
Well, we weren't gonna
be able to stay focused anyway.
S'pose you're right.
That's right. I haven't met
his father or younger brother yet.
I wonder what kind of people they are?
So, uh, your younger brother,
what's his name?
Tota. Take "to"
from the word "transparent,"
and "ta" from my name, and you get "Tota."
Tota!
Do you look like each other?
Yeah.
He's basically a smaller me.
A smaller you?!
- And what about your father?
- Huh? My father?
We, uh... Hmm...
Actually, I'm not sure if we look alike.
Nah, I don't think that
there's much resemblance at all.
But, then again, Pin and my mom
are both constantly going on about
how similar my father and I look.
So you do look alike?
Uh-- Well-- No.
I really don't think we do.
- The Kazehaya of the past...
- He's a coach, isn't he?
- Yeah.
- ...and the Kazehaya of the future!
Stretching time!
One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight!
Two, two, three, four...
Did you see that TV show
about ghosts last night? It was so scary!
What? No way! You know
there's no such thing as ghosts, right?
Yes, there is!
There was this skinny girl in
a white dress, walking through the grass.
And she had super long hair.
- Nah! Well, I like curvy girls better.
- I don't remember if she had curves.
But, she was walking around
with what looked like a plastic bag.
Whoa!
Just like that girl over there!
Exactly like that!
Whoa!
Hey!
You can't just skip the exercises!
Tota.
Well, there he is.
This is my little brother.
He... he's like a mini Kazehaya!
Hi there! I-- it's nice to meet you!
- Uh, I'm Sawako Ku--
- So, like, are you Shota's woman?
-"Woman"?!
- Hey, what's going on?
- That's Shota's woman.
- Really?
- Ow!
- Might've said too much.
What? Isn't she your woman?
- Wait, is she not?
- What's going on.
We are together,
but don't call her my "woman."
- So it is true!
- Oh, you were right!
- You're so right!
- Hey, nice catch, Shota!
That's enough outta you guys.
Well, I'm Sawako Kuronuma.
It-- it's very nice to meet you.
Sawako!
Just like that?
You look like a ghost!
- She's flat as a board.
- Yeah, you got that right.
- She got nothin'.
- Nothin' at all.
I can't lie.
Not much going on around here.
Tota, shut up!
Look over there. Here comes my father.
It's Kazehaya... of the future!
The future?!
Where's Martinez?
Didn't you bring him with you?
- Oh.
- He was fast asleep.
He was what?
An animal lover?
Well, I hope you at least
brought the ice cream manjū I like.
- I did. No need to get fussy.
- Just hurry up and hand it over.
Hmm? And who are you supposed to be?
This is Sawako Kuronuma, my classmate.
And my girlfriend.
Girlfriend, huh?
I believe I was asking
the young lady who she was.
Why were you the one who answered?
He's right!
Dad, I'm gonna need you
to mind your tone.
I-- I apologize for the delay.
If you would please allow me
the honor of introducing myself.
Show me what you got!
Nice to meet you.
Many know me as, um,
uh, a classmate of Shota's.
They call me Sawako Kuronuma.
In Kitamachi, within Kitahoro,
is where I live.
Father works for the city,
while my mother is a housewife.
At school, I have taken on the duty
of tending to the herb garden.
When I have a day off, um, the activities
I often enjoy include various crafts,
like baking sweets and drawing...
More recently,
I have started listening to rakugo CDs
while diving into
extensive research about ghost stories.
At the moment, I am not a member
of any of the extracurricular clubs
at my high school.
However, should a rakugo club come around,
boy-oh-boy, would I want to partake
in a club like that.
That's enough.
What I really want to know is
are you sure you're eating properly?
I've never seen such skinny arms.
I try to eat three meals a day
to 80% fullness each time.
- Well, try to eat more.
- Sir!
How 'bout exercise?
I-- I maintain my strength
by running once every week.
Oh, and I do
some aerobic exercise every day too.
Good. Sawako, which item
will you choose to consume?
Huh? Oh, I haven't thought about it yet.
What do you have to think about?
The manjū' s right there.
- It's the best!
- Okay!
- So what do you think? Good, right?
- Yes! It's good!
Exactly.
Here we go!
One, two! One, two, three, four.
One, two! One, two, three...
Your dad, he's very much
like a typical father, isn't he?
I think the difference
between him and my dad is dignity.
Dignity?
I guess that's one way to put it,
but I always thought he was a bad father.
Really?
Hey, you there!
That's enough chit-chat!
All right, pick up the pace!
Oh, he's talking to the kids.
Or is he doing it on purpose? Maybe.
You know, Kuronuma, I think he likes you.
He likes you, Sawako.
Mom, Tota, Dad, and Maru...
The whole Kazehaya family.
- Huh? Are you heading home now?
- Yeah.
Perfect timing!
Here. Inari sushi from my mom!
Mmm, thanks.
You're just gonna
eat that right here?!
Well, yeah, I'm hungry.
I mean,
I guess your practice did go kinda late.
And you? How was the review class?
I feel like
my brain's gonna explode.
You studied more
for the entrance exams, right?
Well, yeah... duh! Of course I did.
I really wanted to get in.
My brother... already graduated, y'know?
Huh?! Hold on. Why do you think
I wanted to get into Kitahoro?
Because it's the school
my brother graduated from, right?
It's because that's where
you were going, Ryu!
Just think.
Let's say you got into Kitahoro,
and I went somewhere else.
We'd be going to different schools.
If our teams met at baseball prelims,
then am I... supposed to root
against your school?
I couldn't bring myself to do that!
'Cause I wanna...
I wanna cheer for you, Ryu.
And no one else but you!
Chizuru...
What's wrong with you?
Don't look at me! You big dumb idiot!
I'm going home.
Hey, the heck are you doing?
Thank you.
You're a big giant colossal idiot!
Idiot.